What are we going to do now, Staff?
我们现在打算做什么，Staff？
The main door should keep the fungus out of the tunnels for a bit./ We must warn the others that HQ's had it.
这道门应该能把真菌网挡住一阵
我们必须警告其他人总部已经沦陷了
Right.
是
Well, come on, then.
那就快来
Oh, oh no, not me.
噢，不，不要找我
You're not disobeying an order, are you, Evans?
你不服从命令是吗，Evans？
Now look here, Staff. If we go up there, and this stuff breaks out, we'll be trapped!
Now look, lad, you're scared, that's understandable. /36.1
听着小子，你害怕，这是可以理解德
But you've been in the Army long enough to know that orders is orders. /39.1
但你在军队待得够久了，知道命令就是命令
There's four people up there. If we don't warn them, they're for the chop.
上面有四个人，如果我们不警告他们，他们就任凭宰割了
So? Four of them's getting the chop - there's no reason to make it six, is there?
所以啊，他们四个被宰割，没理由要变成六个啊，对不？
I've had enough of your lip for one day. Now come on! Follow me.
今天一天我算是受够你那张破嘴了。现在快点，跟着我
Evans! Come back here!
Evans！回来！
Not on your nelly! Cheerio, Staff!
Right, lad - I'll get you for this!
Anne...
Hey!
Stop! Come back here!
Stop! Anne, I've been thinking. Until we know who else is working for the Intelligence, everyone must be suspect.
停下！Anne，我一直在想。在我们确切知道谁在为大智慧工作以前，每个人都是有嫌疑的
Yes?
Well, the fewer people who know this chap's on our side, the better.
知道这个家伙在我们这边的人，越少越好
Yes... yes, and whoever is the Intelligence is bound to know that you're controlling this Yeti.
是的，不管谁是大智慧，他肯定知道是你在控制这个雪怪
Mmm... I know.
嗯... 我知道
You are to remain here for... Do you think a minute will be enough?
你在这里停留...你觉得一分钟够不够？
What for?
够干什么？
For us to get clear.
够我们俩闪人
Perhaps.
也许吧
You are to remain here for ninety seconds, and then resume acting on orders from the Intelligence
你在这里停留90秒，然后继续按照大智慧的命令行动
until you are told otherwise. Is that understood?
直到你得到其它指示，明白了吗
Right. Switch off, for ninety seconds, starting from... now.
好。关闭90秒，从现在...开始！
Come on, Anne.
快来，Anne
It is them! Come on!
是它们，快点
Am I glad to see you! There's fungus at Warren Street.
见到你们真高兴！Warren 街也有真菌了
Yes, I know.
是的，我知道
Oh. What are you doing down here, anyway?
噢，你在这下面干什么？
Well, as a matter of fact...
这个，事实上...
I'll tell you another time. Hello, Colonel.
我回头再告诉你。你好，上校
Glad to see you're both safe. Any luck with your gadgets?
看见你俩都安全真是太好了。你们那小玩意运气怎么样？
No. No, I'm afraid not.
不，恐怕不怎么样
Pity.
真遗憾
Any news of Victoria?
有 Victoria 的消息吗？
Yes, she's at Piccadilly Station.
有，她在 Piccadilly 站
Piccadilly?
Is my father there too?
我父亲也在那里吗？
Aye, he's with her.
是，他俩在一块
Are they alright?
都还好吗？
Yes.
是的
How do you know?
你怎么知道的
Ran across Arnold - he saw them.
碰到了 Arnold，他看见过他们
Arnold?
Arnold! But Evans said - the fungus...
Arnold！但 Evans 说过，那些真菌....
Yes, he went into it, alright, but he came out again somehow. /
是的，他走进去了，确实，但不知怎的他又出来了
Says he can't remember what happened.
他说他想不起来发生了什么
Well we haven't got any time to find out.
我们也没时间去搞明白
No, time's nearly up.
没有，时间快到了
Yes, your twenty minutes.
是，你那二十分钟
Well come on, then.
那就，来吧
What are you going to do?
你打算做什么？
We can't do anything until we get back to Headquarters, /10.2
在回到总部之前我们什么也做不了
and... then, if we've got time, we'll try and increase the range of the control units. Come on!
如果我们还有时间，我们要尽量增加控制器的距离。快点
What is it, Colonel?
什么事，上校？
Something up ahead.
前面有什么东西
We can't go back!
我们回不去了！
What, fungus, you mean?
什么，有真菌网，是这个意思吗？
Yes.
是的
Is that you, Colonel?
是你吗，上校？
It's Arnold. Hang on, Staff!
是 Arnold。坚持住，Staff
Why isn't he in HQ?
他怎么不在总部？
Sir - the fungus. It's swamped HQ.
头儿，那些真菌网，已经侵占了总部
No!
不！
I'm afraid so, sir. The main doors should keep it out of the tunnels for a bit, but...
恐怕如此。大门还能把它挡在隧道外面，但是...
Where's Evans?
Evans 在哪儿？
Scarpered, sir.
跑掉了，头儿
Our time's up! We're all together - they've come to fetch us!
我们的时间到了！我们聚在一起，他们来带我们走了
H... hello! If you... if you're looking for your friend, he went that way...
你...你好！如果你...你在找你的朋友，他去那边了...
Look, you don't want me!... I'm not one of them, see?... /03.5
Driver, that's what I am... shouldn't be down here at all, really...
我说，你不会想要我的！... 我不是他们中的一员，明白？
司机，我只是个司机... 真不该下这里来的，真的...
Hey, steady on!
嗨，稳住！
Oh, going for a walk, are we? There's lovely.
噢，要散散步，是吗？好温馨啊
I'm going to make a break for it, sir.
我打算冲出去，头儿
Think you can?
你觉得你能？
Well, it's worth a try. On the loose, sir, I might be able to do something./
If only you could distract them, sir.
至少，值得试一试。fix me
但你要帮忙吸引他们的注意力，头儿
Right, Staff.
好，Staff
I think it wants us to go on, sir.
我觉得它想要我们继续走，头儿
Right. Here we go.
好吧，那就走
Wait!... Can't you see, he's fallen over!
等等！... 你没看到吗，他摔倒了！
Be careful, be careful!
小心点，小心！
Where are we being taken, Professor?
我们要被带到哪儿去，教授？
Oh, to meet the Intelligence, I suppose.
哦，去见大智慧，我估计
A pyramid!
一座金字塔！
Yes - but it's different! We... we've never seen one like this before. It's fascinating! /
是的，但有些不一样，我们...之前从没见过这个样子的。很吸引人！
This must be the machine that the Intelligence intends using on the Doctor.
这肯定就是大智慧说要用在博士身上的那个机器
Oh, no no. No, I shouldn't if I was you.
噢，不，不。我要是你的话我就不会
Yes, I think perhaps you're right.
是的，我想也许你是对的
Why didn't you tell me all this before?
为什么之前不告诉我这些情况？
Him.
他
You don't think the Colonel...
你不是说上校他...
Well, you never know, do you?
但是，你也不知道啊，对不对？
Which one is ours?
哪个是我们的？
I don't know.
我不知道
What!
什么！
Well unfortunately I've lost track of him.
很不幸，我没跟住它
Oh, that's a great help!
噢，那可帮大忙了！
Well, never mind, I... I want you to take this microphone/?
and keep on calling our Yeti to you.
这个，别管了...我要你拿着这个麦克风
一直呼叫，把我们的雪怪叫到你身边来
How will I know I've got the right one?
我怎么知道过来的对的？
Well, you'll soon know if you haven't got the right one, won't you! /24.5
Jamie, I hope you don't suffer from claustrophobia!
哦，如果不对的话，你很快就会知道，是吧？
Jamie，我期望你没有幽闭恐怖症
Sergeant! Oh, oh thank heavens I found you! /?
I've been wondering down here by myself for... for ages!
中士, 感谢老天我找到你了！
我一个人在这下面转悠了好几个世纪了！
Well well well, quite forgotten about you, we had, Mr Chorley!
喔喔喔，我们都快忘记你了，Chorley 先生
Tried to get out over the surface, but... there were Yeti everywhere! /53.5
试过逃到地面上去，但是...到处都有雪怪！
And there's this... this fungus, and fog, all around, you see, and... it's hopeless! /02.5
而这里有这个...真菌网，有雾，到处都是，你看，还有... 完全没希望
Where's the control box?
控制盒在哪儿？
Hm?
嗯？
The control box!
控制盒！
It's in my pocket.
在我口袋里
Well, why don't you use it on these Yeti? And then maybe we can escape!
怎么，你怎么不对这些雪怪使用？那样的话也许我们能逃出去
Oh, no. I must meet the Intelligence face to face.
哦，不。我必须跟大智慧面对面
Doctor?
博士？
What is it?
什么事？
Been thinking - the Yeti haven't noticed McCrimmon's disappearance yet./29.5
Not that I think he'll be able to achieve anything.
我在想，雪怪还没有留意到 McCrimmon 已经不见了
倒不是说我觉得他能搞定什么
Go on...
继续...
Well, I don't really know how to say this, but, um... there's Miss Travers and Victoria to think of, and, er...
这个...我真不知道该怎么说，但是... 有 Travers 小姐和 Victoria 要考虑，还有 ...
You mean, am I going to give myself up?
你是说，我是不是会放弃我自己？
Yes. Of course, the decision must be yours, and yours alone. /?
But the Intelligence did promise to release Travers and Victoria.
是的。当然，决定是你自己下，一个人下
但大智慧的确承诺过会放了 Travers 和 Victoria
You believe that?
你相信吗？
Well, why not?
怎么，为什么不？
Hello, we've got company.
哈罗，我们有同伴了
Hello, sir!
Evans, where the devil have you been?
Evans，见鬼你去哪儿了？
Didn't Staff Arnold tell you, sir?
Staff Arnold 没有告诉你吗，头儿？
Yes. Sounded very like desertion to me.
是。听起来我像是被抛弃了
Desertion? Me? Oh, good heavens, no! /11.2
抛弃？我？噢，老天，不会！
No, I... I thought I'd try a single-handed and desperate attempt to rescue Professor Travers and the girl!
不，我还想我要单枪匹马死命去救 Travers 教授和这个女孩儿呢
Isn't Staff Arnold about?
Staff Arnold 在这附近吗？
No.
不在
Good!
好！
Listen!
听！
Now listen, everyone - when the Yeti come for you, don't struggle.
听好，所有人。当雪怪过来的时候，不要挣扎
Whatever you do, don't resist them!
你们做什么都行，但不要反抗！
Don't struggle, he says! He must be joking!
别挣扎，他说！他肯定在开玩笑
The Doctor will have to give in. There's no other choice!
博士只能投降，没有别的选择
Aye, aye, time to get fell in!
Thank you!
谢谢你！
Father! Oh, father, are you alright?
父亲！噢，父亲，你没事吧？
Yes, I'm alright again... Don't, don't worry, Anne.
是的，我又没事了... 别，别担心，Anne
Jamie and the Doctor - where are they?
Jamie 和博士，他们在哪儿？
Anne?
Come towards me... Like that, that's it... Come to...
朝我这边来..就这样，对了... 到...
Right now. Raise your right arm.
好了，举起你的右臂
Raise your right arm!
举起你的右臂！
Oh, what's the use?
噢，这有什么用？
Well, there's nothing to be afraid of, dear. Just - just be calm.
好，没什么可害怕的，亲爱的。只要 - 保持冷静
Doctor!
博士
The Doctor!
Doctor!
博士
What are they going to do?
他们打算干什么？
Now don't worry, Victoria.
不用担心，Victoria
But... I...
但是...我...
Everything's under control. Don't be frightened.
一切都在掌控之中，别害怕
But Doctor, what are they going to do?
但是博士，他们要干什么？
Everything is under control. Tell her, Anne, you understand?
一切都在掌控之中。告诉她，Anne，你明白吗？
Yes... yes, I think so.
是的，我想我明白
Now listen, everyone. Don't do anything foolish! I am perfectly alright.
现在听着，所有人。别做任何傻事！我完全没事
Yes, he is perfectly alright. Thank you, Doctor, for being so cooperative.
是的，他完全没事。谢谢你这么合作，博士
Why don't you show yourself? Who are you?
为什么你不现身呢？你是谁？
Silence! You will know soon enough.
安静！很快你就知道了
Chorley!
Good grief!
老天！
But that horrible little man...
但那个恐怖的小家伙...
You, the Intelligence?
你？是大智慧？
No... no!
不，不x
No no no, he can't be the Intelligence, he can't! It doesn't make sense!
不不不，他不可能是大智慧，不可能！这说不通！
It isn't me! It isn't me, don't you understand! /28.3
I'm not the Intelligence! The Intelligence is him!
不是我，不是我，你不明白吗？
我不是大智慧！大智慧是他！
It can't be!
不可能！
Oh. Arnold
No. Merely Arnold's lifeless body in which I have concealed myself./45.3
不，我只是把自己藏在 Arnold 已经没有生命的身体里
But let us to work. There will be time for discussion later. /?
In fact, all the time in the world.
我们还是办正事吧。后面会有讨论时间的
实际上，世界上所有的时间
Oh... so you weren't going to let us go then, afterwards?
噢... 所以你不打算放我们走，完事以后m
Did you think he would?
你还以为他会？
The last member of the party. Come and join us!
聚会的最后一位成员，来，加入我们吧
Oh, Jamie!
噢，Jamie！
Victoria, are you alright?
Victoria，你没事吧
Your solicitude is touching. Nevertheless, it is wasting time.
你的关怀让人感动。不管怎样，这是浪费时间
Frightened that something might go wrong?
是在害怕出什么事吗？
Join the Doctor.
去博士那儿吧
Do what he says, Jamie.
按他说的做，Jamie
Take him!
带走他！
Leave him! Leave him be!
别动他！别动他！
I must ensure your complete cooperation, Doctor. /
必须确保你会完全合作
Should you prove at all unhelpful, your young friend's neck will be broken.
一旦证明你不太合作, 你这年轻朋友的脖子就断了
You gave your word that no one would be harmed. I refuse to submit until you release Jamie!
你保证过不会有人受到伤害的。我拒绝服从, 直到你释放 Jamie!
Alright. Release the boy!
好吧，放开那孩子！
But at the first sign of trouble from you...
但是一旦发现你有任何制造麻烦的迹象...
Don't worry. I will do what you say.
别担心，你说什么我做什么
Good. Into the machine, Doctor.
很好，到机器里去，博士
Soon your mind will be absorbed by the Great Intelligence.
You should be very proud, Doctor - your knowledge of the past will help to shape the future of this planet.
很快你的意识都会被大智慧所吸收
你应该会很骄傲，博士，你在过去积累的知识见有助于塑造这个星球未来
Just get on with it, please.
直接开始吧，请
You seem very anxious suddenly.
你似乎突然变得焦急了
I just want it over and done with.
我就想快点结束它
Submission is essential. You must understand, Doctor
提交过程是很重要的。你必须明白，博士
...that without your complete cooperation,  this transference would be of no value
...如果你不完全合作，传送就没有价值
Should you offer any opposition, either physical or mental,
如果你做出任何抵抗，无论是身体上的还是精神上的
I shall be forced to punish you, or rather your friends. /21
我都会被迫惩罚你, 或者更确切地说, 惩罚你的朋友。
Prepare for a great darkness to cloud your mind.
准备好，会有一团黑暗罩住你的意识
Attack now! Attack the Yeti!
开始攻击！攻击那些雪怪！
Stop it! Stop it!
停下！停下！
Get Arnold!
No, Jamie, no!
不，Jamie，不要
Come on, get the Doctor out!
快，把博士弄出来！
No, you don't understand, you'll ruin everything! No!
不，你不明白！你会破坏了一切！不！
Professor! Anne! Give us some help!
教授！Anne！帮我们一下！
No! No!... No! Leave me be! You don't understand, I've got to stay here!
不不！... 不！别管我！你们没明白，我必须待在这里！
Well, that's that then, innit?
You blithering Welsh imbecile! Why can't you do what you're told?
你个爱叨叨的威尔士草包！为什么不能跟你说什么就做什么呢？
Hey, now just a minute, Doctor! If we hadn't pulled you out of that, you'd have been a heap of dust by now.
嗨，现在等一下，博士！如果我们没把你从那里面拉出来，你现在已经是一堆黄土了
You're just as bad. I told you to leave it to me! Now you've gone and ruined everything!
你就好了？我告诉过你别管我！现在你破坏了一切！
Ruined every - How can we! We... we've won, haven't we?
破坏了一...我们怎么能！我们...我们赢了，是吧？
No!
没有！
What do you mean, Doctor?
你什么意思，博士
Oh, why didn't they leave it to me?
I had crossed those wires on that helmet thing.
噢，为什么他们就不能别管我呢？我已经反转了那个头盔里面的项圈
The Intelligence wouldn't have drained me, I had... would have drained the Intelligence!
大智慧吸收不了我的意识，我本来...还可以吸收他的！
As it is, all it got was a crossed circuit!
当前来说，就只有一个反转的线圈x
You mean, all we've done is... is cut off its contact with Earth,
你是说，我们所干的事情是... 切断了他跟地球的联系
it's - it's still out there in space somewhere, flying around?
他，他还在太空中某个地方，飘着？
Precisely! Look!
正是！看！
Oh!
噢！
Oh, poor fellow!
噢，可怜的家伙！
Do you mean to say that Arnold wasn't the Intelligence?
你的意思是说 Arnold 不是大智慧？
No. He was just a poor soldier that was taken over. He was probably one of the first to disappear.
不，他只是个被附体的可怜士兵。他可能是第一个消失的
You mean it might come back?
你的意思是他还可能回来？
Well, it's still around, isn't it? I've failed.
那，他在在附近，是吗？我已经失败了
Nonsense, man!
胡说！
You were marvellous.
你太了不起了
Yes. Great victory.
是，大获全胜
I doubt it.
我表示怀疑
No - you were a hero, and you know it.
不，你是个英雄，你知道的
You don't really think so. Do you?
你其实并不这么想，是吗？
Yes, yes I do.
我是这么想
You've got to face facts, old man. Tomorrow you're going to be a household word, a national figure...
你得面对事实，老头。明天你将成为一个家喻户晓的词, 一个全国性的人物.....
Oh no, oh no!
噢不，噢不！
Yeah! I want you on my television programme, and...
好！我要你上我的电视节目，还要...
Jamie! Victoria! Come along, it's time we left!
Jamie! Victoria! 快过来，我们该走了
...but the Press Conference, Doctor!
...但是新闻发布会，博士
Goodbye!
再见！
But Doctor, Doctor, you... you can't go yet, there are a lot of things I want to discuss with you!
但是，博士，博士，你...你还不能走。还有好多事情我需要和你讨论！
I'm sorry, Travers, we have to go.
抱歉，Travers，我们必须得走了
Where are you going?
你们要去哪儿？
Covent Garden! Come along. Come along, Jamie.
科文特花园！快过来，快过来，Jamie
Bye!... Bye.
拜拜
Where's he going?
他要去哪儿？
Huh? Oh, er, back to his TARDIS, I suppose.
啥？哦，回他的 TARDIS，我估计
You mean this, uh, this time machine thing, it really exists?
你是说这个...这个时间机器，他真的存在？
Y... well I, er... oh, explain it to him, Anne, will you?
这个...噢，你跟他解释一下吧，Anne，行吗？
Colonel, I think we'd better check up top, don't you?
上校，我想我们最好上去坚持一下，你觉得呢
Right, Professor. Evans!
行，教授。Evans！
Father - father, I...
父亲，父亲，我...
Now don't you go, Miss Travers, I'd er, I'd like you to explain all about this, this time machine for me.
你现在别走，Travers 小姐，我要...我要你给我讲解一下这个，这个时间机器
Oh dear...!
噢天啊....！
Well, where do we go? Which is the way to Covent Garden?
那，我们去哪儿？哪条路是去科文特花园的？
Oh, don't ask me. I've completely lost my bearings.
噢，别问我，我完全失去了方向
All these tunnels look the same to me.
所有的隧道在我看来都是一样
Come on, let's try this way.
来吧，我们试试这边
Well it doesn't matter, anyway. I mean, there's no danger, is there?
不管哪边都没有关系，我是说，没有危险了，是吗？
Well, not from the Yeti, no, but who knows, they might suddenly start the trains again! Come on!
只是没有雪怪的危险。但是，谁知道呢，他们可能突然开动一条列车过来！快点！
Trains?
列车？
Oh!
噢！
Come on!
快点！
There's someone there...
What?
There!
Who's that? Who is it? D'you see who it was?
No. Do you think it could have been...
The Intelligence? If only we could do something!
I'm sure the Doctor will think of something.
No, not this time, Victoria. The Doctor would never risk the chance of the Intelligence harming you.
You mean he'll just give in?
Yes, I'm afraid so. Afraid there's no alternative.
Yes, you're right, Professor. He has no alternative. I am sorry not to be here to welcome you personally, but I am sure you will not be offended. After all, the guest of honour is the Doctor - he, I am sure, will cooperate, as I advise you to do. Any attempt to interfere would be pointless. My Yeti can destroy you so easily.
It's all my fault! If I hadn't tampered with that sphere - people killed, London invaded, all because of my wretched curiosity!
Don't blame yourself, Professor.
Why not? I... I've sacrificed you all! And for what?
My, my, my, we are in a state, aren't we, sir?
Yes... alright... no, I'm fine. I've just been so scared, that's all!
'S alright, sir, nothing to be ashamed of.
Yes.
There's just one thing that puzzles me though, sir.
Oh, what's that?
How you managed to exist all this time - why didn't the Yetis get you?
I'm sorry, what are you suggesting? You're not suggesting that I...
Oh no, sir, I was just wondering, that's all. I think perhaps you'd better come along with me, don't you, sir? Come on, now.